<DOC>
<TEXT>
Soon after the <GPE>Libyan</GPE> rebellion escalated, a senior member of the nation's powerful <Person>Warfallah</Person> tribe announced it would no longer support <Person>Moammar Gadhafi</Person>, saying that "he is no longer a brother."

The <Person>Zawiya</Person> tribe, based in a petroleum-rich region in the east, threatened to cut off oil flow. The <Person>Bani Walid</Person> tribe decided to withdraw its men from the regime's security brigades. And the influential <Person>Zintan</Person> tribe, allied in the past to <Person>Gadhafi</Person>'s own tribe, broadcast a statement of support for the opposition.

One after another, <GPE>Libya</GPE>'s myriad tribes are falling in line against <Person>Gadhafi</Person>, and the implications are enormous, said longtime observers of <GPE>Libya</GPE>, because for centuries, tribes have formed the backbone of the <Location>North African</Location> nation.

Many Americans pride themselves on <Person>God</Person> and country. In <GPE>Libya</GPE>, it's <Person>God</Person>, tribe, then country. 
</TEXT>
</DOC>
